Guide to the Papers of Serge A. Korff 1928-1989 MC 110 MC 110
New York University Archives
Serge A. Korff Papers
1928-1989
MC 110
New York University Archives
12.0 Linear feet (8 boxes)
Serge A. Korff was a prominent cosmic ray physicist active in academic, governmental and international settings whose tenure at NYU was from 1941-1989. The collection encompasses Korff's professional career and includes correspondence with leading American, South American and European physicists, graduate students and post-doctoral fellows, academicians from other disciplines, professional scientific organizations, government agencies, military personnel, commercial equipment suppliers, and publishing concerns. Also included in the collection is information on research projects and expeditions; grant proposals and reports; materials on scientific conferences; students' theses and dissertations; administrative records pertaining to NYU and its physics department; and reprints of scholarly articles by Korff and others.
Korff, Serge Alexander, 1906-
Separated Material
No documentation of anything separated from the collection.
Related Material at the New York University Archives
Arrangement
Organized alphabetically by correspondent, and (less frequently) by topic. Personal and professional correspondence is filed by name of correspondent, and institutional correspondents by organization. Recommendations and obituaries are filed under the name of theindividual discussed. Some files in this series include drafts and reprints of brief articles by Korff (for example, encyclopedia articles have been filed under the name of the publisher); others contain drafts by colleagues which Korff informally reviewed. Certain materials have been assigned topical folder titles, such as "Mailing lists and addresses" and "Invitations."
Organized in six series: I. Correspondence; II. Notes, drafts and photographs; III. Research projects; IV. Organizations and conferences; V. Academia; and VI. Published materials.
Scope and Content Note
The collection reflects the work and perspective of a scientist whose life work was devoted to understanding the universe and sharing that knowledge with as wide an audience as possible. The Korff Collection documents the work of a prominent cosmic ray physicist active in academic, governmental and international settings. The collection contains 10 linear feet of correspondence, notes, photographs, manuscripts, and printed material documenting research grants, academic activities, professional organizations, conferences, and publications. Korff's work from 1928 to 1989 is reflected; the bulk of the material representing the period 1950-1980. There is a largely undocumented area in this collection: the first is Korff's work prior to his affiliation with NYU, while the second coincides with World War II.
Correspondents include leading American, South American and European physicists, graduate students and post-doctoral fellows, academicians from other disciplines, professional scientific organizations, government agencies, military personnel, and publishing concerns. Significant physicists represented include Manuel Sandoval Vallarta, Robert A. Millikan, Willard F. Libby, and Gabriel Alvial. Korff's notes and drafts detail research methods and prose style, lectures and presentations, revisions of his own and other's publications, and a wealth of experimental data, particularly photographs of eclipses and other astronomical events and field notes from high altitude experiments. The collection documents research projects and expeditions; grant proposals, reports and correspondence; scientific conferences; students' work; administrative records of NYU and its physics department; and reprints of scholarly articles by Korff and others.
The Korff Collection provides critical insight into the field of physics, and science in general, in the 20th century. Significant topics represented include the study of cosmic rays, neutrons and optical dispersion; the theory, development and uses of devices for measuring radiation; radio-carbon dating; physics research and its social and political context around the world; international scientific cooperation, particularly the International Geophysical Year, 1957-58; observations of eclipses and astronomical events; high altitude balloon flights; and government and military funding of scientific research. File titles marked with an asterisk in the Folder Listings contain interesting images or significant documents. A folder of biographical information on Korff precedes Series I.
Historical/Biographical Note:
Sergei Alexander Korff was born in Helsingfors, Finland, in 1906. Immigrating to the United States with his family in 1917, he became a citizen in 1927. Korff attended Princeton receiving his A.B. in 1928, M.A. in 1929 and Ph.D. in 1931. Between 1932 and 1940, he completed research fellowships at the Mt. Wilson Observatory, the California Institute of Technology, the Carnegie Institute of Washington, and the Bartol Research Foundation. Collaborating with eminent physicists in his early work, Korff investigated topics such as optical dispersion, proportional counters and neutron measurements in cosmic radiation. Korff began his tenure at New York University in 1941, and continued there until his death in 1989. He helped train at least three generations of students, taking many on research expeditions as far away as the North Pole and the South Seas.
In addition to his teaching and research, Korff lent his efforts to the international scientific community. He compiled the report of the Joint Commission on High Altitude Research for ICSU-UNESCO; served on the Cosmic Ray Technical Panel for the International Geophysical Year, 1957-58; organized the pole-to-pole Rockwell Scientific Round-the-World Flight in 1965; and encouraged and secured support for scientific work around the world, particularly in Central and South America. Notable among his numerous professional affiliations were his terms as president of the Explorer's Club (1955-1958); the American Geographical Society (1966-1971); and New York Academy of Science (1972). For his efforts to transfer surplus scientific equipment to the decimated laboratories of France after World War II, in 1952 Korff was decorated Chevalier of the Legion of Honor. For the contribution of his radiation detection devices to the study of cancer, he was awarded the Curie Medal of the International Union Against Cancer.
Korff's Counter Project and Cosmic Ray Project attracted numerous students to NYU; many later achieved prominence as physicists. The project also brought the university substantial funding from government agencies, such as the National Air and Space Agency and the National Science Foundation. Author of over 150 scientific papers and books, as well as a number of works on exploration, geology and stamps, Korff's contributions to science went beyond the study of cosmic rays. His ability to render complex scientific issues exciting and clear to the general public in encyclopedia and newspaper articles, and to expose the subtleties of science to his students and peers, marked Korff as an outstanding figure in 20th century physics.
Access Restrictions
Open to researchers.
Provenance
This collection was transferred to the University Archives by Rosalind Mendell of the NYU Physics deptartment.
American Geographical Society of New York.; Cosmic Ray Technical Panel.; David, William O.; Explorers Club.; Joint Commission on High Altitude Research.; Korff, Serge Alexander, 1906-; Libby, Leona Marshal, 1919-; Libby, Willard F.; Mendell, Rosalind B.; New York Academy of Sciences.; New York University. Dept. of Physics.; Sandoval Vallarta, Manuel.; Admnistrative records.; Atmosphere physics.; Correspondence; Cosmic physics.; Cosmic ray neutrons.; Dispension.; Dissertations.; Drafts (documents).; Grant proposals.; Memoirs.; New York (State)--New York.; Photographs; Physics -- Political aspects.; Physics -- Social aspects.; Physics -- Study and teaching -- United States.; Proportional counters.; Radiation -- Measurement.; Reports.; Reprints.; Researching.; Science -- International cooperation.
- Series I: Correspondence
  - A - B, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04225407 1
  - Alvial, Gabriel, 1956-1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Australia trip, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bjorksten, Johan, 1976-1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bowman, Isaiah, 1976-1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - C - D, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Clute, Timothy R. 1980-81, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Cobas, Amador, 1948-1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Cosmos Club, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - E - F, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Funk & Wagnalls, Inc./Standard Reference Library, 1969-1978 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - G - H, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Grolier, Inc. New Book of Knowledge, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - I - J - K, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Invitations, 1953-1983, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Instituto Geofisico del Peru, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - L - M, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Libby, Leona Marshall, 1973-1984 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Libby, Leona Marshall, draft articles, 1971-1981, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Libby, Willard Frank, 1956-1980 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Lobbying, 1957-1982 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Mailing lists and addresses, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Millikan, Robert A., 1935-1937 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - N - O - P - Q, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Pierce, Keith A., 1962-1972 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Pregel, Boris, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Prentice-Hall, Inc., 1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Prescott, John R., 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - R - S, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Ralph, Elizabeth K., 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Requests for reprints, 1970-1984 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Scribner, Kimball J., 1981-1985 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Sekido, Yataro, 1982-1986 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Simpson, John A., 1976 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - South Africa trip, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - St. Vincent's, British West Indies, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Stravon Educational Press, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - T - U - V, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Unidentified correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - University of Wyoming, Archive of Contemporary History, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - U. S. Atomic Energy Commission, Rainwater samples, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Vallarta, Manuel Sandoval, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - W - X - Y - Z, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Weyer, Edward M., 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Series II: Notes
  - Subseries A: Lecture outlines, laboratory and field observations notes and calculations
    Scope and Contents note
    (not explicitly linked to any specific project or event)
    - Astronomical observations, 1925-1986, undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Spectral dispersion, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Field notes, books I-V: 1960s encompass 1 volume, 1938, 1964-1969 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Lab. notebook, Bartol Research Foundation and NYU, 1940-1946 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Laboratory Note Book, 1947-1965 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - European trip, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Tables, charts and diagrams, ca.1950-1960, undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Lecture outlines [non-NYU], 1956-1976 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Rocket calculations, ca.1957 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Asia trip, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Unidentified notes, 1959-1971, undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Astronomical bodies and laws, ca.1960-1970 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Notes on the Third Derivative Term inthe Equations of Motion, ca.1963 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Barcode #: 3 1142 04225408 9
    - Solar events: May and November, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Eclipse, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "Some Comments on Neutrons at Sealevel", 1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Lab notebook, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      [labelled "Field Notes 1937-Peru" but several signatures have been removed; most of the pages are unused]
    - "The Double Plateau Effect", undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - "The Origins of Stratospheric Science in the United States" [introduction and table of contents], undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Annotated citations, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Annotated citations [index cards], undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Clippings, 1969-1985, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Clippings, Halley's Comet, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Subseries B: Draft articles and manuscripts: Drafts and manuscripts
    - Dispersion, ca.1929 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      (pp. 1-4 missing)
    - Draft articles, 1940-1959 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Satirical Physics, 1941-1948, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - "Cosmic Ray Research" [written for Life magazine], 1948 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Draft articles, 1960-1969 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Draft articles, 1970-1982 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Book reviews, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - "Variations in Radiocarbon Production in the Earth's Atmosphere"SAK and Rosalind B. Mendell, 1979-1981 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Draft articles, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Cosmic Physics, Correspondence and outline, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Cosmic Physics, Chap. 1-2, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Cosmic Physics, Chap. 3-5, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Cosmic Physics, Chap. 6-8, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Cosmic Physics, Chap. 9-12, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Cosmic Physics, Chap. 13-18, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Cosmic Physics, Chap. 19-26; Cosmic Radiation, Project Report for the NYU Cosmic Ray Research Group; table of contents, errata, appendices, ca.1962 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Cosmic Radiation, diagrams and illustrations, ca.1960 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Cosmic Radiation, camera-ready illustrations, ca.1960 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Cosmic Radiation, Chap. 1, ca.1960 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Cosmic Radiation, Chap. 2, ca.1960 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Cosmic Radiation, Chap. 3, ca.1960 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Cosmic Radiation, Chap. 4, ca.1960 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Cosmic Radiation, Chap. 5, ca.1960 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Cosmic Radiation, Chap. 6, ca.1960 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Cosmic Radiation, Chap. 7, ca.1960 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Cosmic Radiation, Chap. 8, ca.1960 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Barcode #: 3 1142 04225409 7
    - Cosmic Radiation, Chap. 9, ca.1960 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Cosmic Radiation, Chap. 10, ca.1960 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Cosmic Radiation, Chap. 11, ca.1960 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Cosmic Radiation, Chap. 12 and 12-cra-1, ca.1960 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Unidentified chapters (10, 11, 12, 13), 1964, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Proportional Counters, diagram, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Draft proposals [partial and unidentified], undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Subseries C: Photographs:
    (images specific to publications or events are filed with those related materials)
    - Lick Observatory (includes photographs of facility and astronomical images taken there), 1893, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous astronomical photographs, 1894-1935, 1960-1970 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Eclipse, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Eclipse, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Solar and planetary spectra, 1963-1967 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Astronomical photographs [taken at Kitt Peaks National Observatory], 1964-1967 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Eclipses, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous photographs, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Series III: Projects, experiments and expeditions
  - Subseries A: Projects, experiments and expeditions not specifically funded by U. S. government agencies
    (arranged alphabetically by project title or grantor, then chronologically where appropriate)
    - List of Research Grants and Contracts, ca.1970 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - High Altitude Flights, Lima, Peru, 1934-1935 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Balloon Flights, Pennsylvania, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Quaker Chemical Products Corp., Study of Cutting Fluids, 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Balloon Flights, 1945-1950 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Inter- University High Altitude Laboratory for Cosmic Physics (IUHAL), Mt. Evans, CO., 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Research Corporation, 1946-1948, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Hyuck Corporation, 1961-1965 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Bellinghausen Expedition (Eclipse, May 30, 1965), 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - LTV Aerospace Corporation [subcontractor for NASA grants 1-5209/1-01282], 1970 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Eclipses, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - International Geophysical Year (IGY), Comite Special (CSAGI), 1955-1957 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - IGY, United States National Committee (USNC), 1953-1959 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - IGY, Subcommittee for Cosmic Intensity Variations (SCRIV), 1955-1957 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - IGY, Technical Panel on Cosmic Rays (TP-CR), ca.1953-1956 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - IGY, TP-CR, 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - IGY, TP-CR, undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - IGY, Cosmic Ray Grants to NYU, 1955-1960 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - IGY, Pan-American participation, 1955-1957 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - IGY, Pan-American participation, 1958-1960, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - IGY, Clippings, trip to South America, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - IGY, Clippings, ca.1957-1960 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - IGY, Miscellaneous, ca.1959 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - International Year of the Quiet Sun (IQSY), 1962-1965 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Subseries B: Government-funded research
    - Federal Communications Corporation, Radio Station Permits, 1957-1958 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Barcode #: 3 1142 04225410 5
    - National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), Elevated Altitude Radiation (NAS W-31), 1959-1961 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - NASA, Space Studies (NsG 167-161), 1961-1967 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - NASA, Experimental Flight Program (NAS 1-5209; NAS 1-10282), 1965-1971 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - NASA, Experimental Flight Program (NAS 1-5209; NAS 1-10282), 1972-1976, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - NASA, Proposal to Study High-energy Neutrons and Possible Solar Neutrons, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - NASA, Atmospheric Neutrons (NAS 1-5209), draft report and data, 1969-1973 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - NASA, Atmospheric Neutrons (NAS 1-5209), project report, ca.1970 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - NASA, Solar- Interplanetary Relationships (NSF 7116), 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - NASA, Effects of Solar Activity on Atmospheric Neutrons Flux (A-9441-B), 1975 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - NASA, Miscellaneous proposals and grants, 1959-1976, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - National Science Foundation (NSF), Cosmic Ray Neutron Monitor, Mt. Wrangell, Alaska(NSF-G8227; G P-855; G P-16568; G P-4211), 1958-1968 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - NSF, Energetic Neutron Studies (NSF G P-4289; G P-1588), 1961-1967 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - NSF, Data Reduction (G A-731), 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - NSF, Variations in Neutrons Produced Largely in the Upper Atmosphere (G A-35962), 1971-1973 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - NSF, Solar-Terrestrial Relationships (G A-41167; DES 74-00667 A01), 1974-1979 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - NSF, Cosmic Ray Decreases and Large Scale Solar Wind Structures (ATM 77-07095), 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - NSF, Miscellaneous proposals and grants, 1955-1974, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Office of Naval Research (ONR) Cosmic Ray Measurement (N6-ONR-279(2); N6-ONR-279(21); ONR-285(2); ONR-285(21)), 1948-1955 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - ONR, Cosmic Ray Measurement (N6-ONR-279(2); N6- ONR-279(21); ONR-285(2); ONR-285(21)), 1956-1963 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - ONR, Miscellaneous Material, 1956-1957, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Pickatinny Arsenal, Feasibility Study and Altitude or Height Sensing Devices (Project 5065), 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - U. S. Air Force Office of Scientific Research (USAF-OSR), Proportional Counters; Cosmic Ray Studies; Cosmic Ray Ballooning (A F 18 (600)-1460; A F 18 (600)-1555; A F 49-638-635), 1955-1957 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - USAF-OSR, Cosmic Ray Studies; Cosmic Ray Ballooning (A F 18(600)-1555; A F 49- 638-635), 1958-1962 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - USAF-OSR, High Altitude Studies; Ballooning Data Reduction, (A F 19 628-378), 1962-1968 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - USAF-OSR, Upper Air Neutron Studies (A F 19-628-378) final report, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - US Naval Radiological Defense Laboratory, and US Army Office of Civil Defense (USA-OCD), Counters (O C D-21311; N O O-228-67- C-1676; D A H C 20-68- C-0137), undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - USA-OCD, Geiger-Mueller Counters (DAHC 20-68- C-0137) final report, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Series IV: Organizations
  - Subseries A: Organizations
    (arranged alphabetically)
    - American Geographical Society (AGS), 1968-1986 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      Barcode #: 3 1142 04225411 3
    - AGS Annual Dinners, 1957-1965 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - AGS Annual Dinners, 1966-1968 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - AGS Annual Dinners, 1969-1973 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - American Institute of Physics, Visiting Scientist Program, 1958-1965 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Committee of Scientific Society Presidents, 1973-1975 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - The Explorers' Club, 1971-1973 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Joint Commission on High Altitude Research Stations, 1952-1956 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - The Lindburgh Memorial Fund, Inc., 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - New York Academy of Science (NYAS), 1971-1972, 1981-1987 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - NYAS, Committee for the Study of Natural Radioactive Substances, 1951-1952 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Societe D'Encouragement au Progres, Paris, 1977-1983 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - United Nations, Executive Committee of Non-Governmental Organizations, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - World Academy of Art and Science (WAAS), American Division, 1960-1979 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - WAAS, American Division, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - WAAS, American Division, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous organizations, 1941-1983 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Subseries B: Conferences
    (arranged chronologically; many folders include correspondence, forms, notes, lecture outlines, drafts and preprints of articles, and photographs related to a conference)
    - American Physics Society, Washington D.C., 1929 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - American Physics Society, Berkeley CA, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Symposium on Cosmic Rays in Honor of Robert A. Millikan's 80th Birthday, CA, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Quinto Congresso Sudamericano de Quimica, Lima, Peru, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Cosmic Ray Conference, Guanajuato, Mexico, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - 3rd International Conference on Ionization Phenomena in Gases, Venice, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - International Conference on Cosmic Rays and the Earth Storm, Kyoto, Japan, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - 5th Interamerican Seminar on Cosmic Radiation, La Paz, Bolivia, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - 6th International Conference on Cosmic Rays, Jaipur, India, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - American Astronomical Society Meeting, Flagstaff AZ, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - American Physical Society Meeting, Mexico City, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - 10th International Conference on Cosmic Rays, Calgary, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - American Geophysical Union Meeting, San Francisco, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - 11th International Conference on Cosmic Rays, Budapest, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - 6th Interamerican Seminar on Cosmic Radiation, La Paz, Bolivia, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - 14th Committee on Space Research (COSPAR) Meeting, Seattle WA, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - 12th International Conference on Cosmic Rays, Hobart, Tasmania, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - 13th International Cosmic Ray Conference, Denver CO, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - "Environment and Society in Transition," 2nd International Joint Conference, WAAS and NYAS, New York, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      Barcode #: 3 1142 04225412 1